let's look at the solution to our page
size quiz our physical memory is 2 GB
our page size is 4 kilobytes how many
page frames we have well a page frame is
a place in physical memory where a page
might fit so the number of frames is
simply 2 GB the physical memory size
divided by the page size the frame is
the same size as a page because it's
basically a place for a page to be in
when we are doing things like this
usually it's a lot easier to think about
this as what power of two is it so 2
gabes is 2 to the 31st bytes 4 kilobytes
is 2 to the 12th bytes so we end up with
2 to the 19th frames so the answer here
is 2 to the 19th how many entries do we
have in each page table we need one
entry in a page table for each page in
the ver memory so the answer here is 4
GB / 4 kiloby and that is 2 to the 20th
or one Mega entry as they would say note
that we need a separate page table for
each process each process is 4 GB of
virtual memory so each process in our
system will need a page table that is
this large 2 to the 20th or slightly
more than 1 million
entries